Kevin Murphy Front-End Developer

kevin.murphy.cool@gmail.com (361) 232-5229 Corpus Christi, TX 78412

Profile

Kevin has over 9 years' experience building web application UI and strong skills in React. Additionally, he has been involved in many practical MERN projects, which is a great bonus to his skills. He is a quick learner, able to pick up new skills and take on a variety of projects and roles with relative ease. He excels at collaborating with his teammates.

Skills

TypeScript | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | React | React Bootstrap | React Query React Hook Form | React Hooks | Redux | Context API | Axios | Styled Component MUI Core | Formik | Joi | Jest | Mocha | Lodash | i18n | Web3.js | Ethers.js TailwindCSS | SCSS | Node.js | Express.js | MongoDB | C / C++ Data Structure & Algorithm | AWS | Git | GitHub | Team Player | Peer Support Stress Management | Time Management | Quality-driven | Communication

Experience

Front-End Developer, *Scopic Software*

Oct 2022 – Jan 2023 | Rutland, MA

I worked in a position of senior front-end developer and mainly developed websites for healthcare, education and business industry. MERN was my top skill, and Laravel and WordPress were also used.

One junior front-end developer was mentored.

I worked remotely full time.

Application Developer, Owny

Apr 2020 - Oct 2022 | Palo Alto, CA

I worked on many projects to transform traditional websites into powerful web3 platforms. Blockchain technology was a key to the projects, and I completed the jobs for NFT token. Three junior developers were mentored, and then they became available to build an infrastructure for the decentralized system more effectively. I worked remotely full time.

Senior Web Developer, Ensemble Group

Apr 2019 – Apr 2020

Corpus Christi, TX

After 2 years and a month in junior developer position, I started to work as a senior developer and then contributed on more projects. I widened the range of stacks to MERN, MEAN and Laravel.

Trading, Education and Health & Fitness were the main industry I worked on. Two Interns were mentored, and then they started to work in a junior position.

Junior Web Developer, Ensemble Group

Mar 2017 – Apr 2019 Corpus Christi, TX

After 7 months of internship, I immediately started working as a junior.

I studied a JavaScript-based framework for frontend and applied it to the project.

React became my top skill, and I mentored an intern to work on a React project together.

Web Developer Intern, Ensemble Group

Sep 2016 – Mar 2017 Corpus Christi, TX

A senior mentored me to work on a React project.

As my skill grows, occasionally did I have opportunities to work on the backend side.

Education

B.S. Computer Science

Texas A&M University-Corpus Christi ⊘

Sep 2012 – Aug 2016 Corpus Christi, TX

Certificates

TripleByte Engineering Certificates *⊘* JavaScript, React, Data Structure & Algorithm

HackerRank Engineering Certificates $\mathscr D$

Problem-Solving Certificate

Interests

Soccer | Medium Blog | Guitar